Brittani Bishop

Technical Project Manager



314.326.0707



brittanibbishop@gmail.com



A St. Louis, MO



LinkedIn

SKILLS

PROFFSSIONAL

Team Leadership Emotional Intelligence Stakeholder Management Strategic Planning Verbal Communication Problem Solvina

TECHNICAL

Microsoft Suite Google Suite HTML and CSS

TOOLS

Jira Slack Agile Methodologies Predictive Methodologies

PROJECTS

FIRST ACADEMY

Spearheaded the implementation of Procare Software within the learning facility to increase productivity in regard to enrollment, record keeping, and billing/tuition.

EDUCATION

Thinkful

Technical Project Immersion 07/2020 - 10/2020 (Remote)

Immersive 3 month Technical Project Management program intended to educate students on systems lifecycles, relevant project management software/technologies, processes, and methodologies to effectively prepare them with relevant skills for the position.

University of Missouri-Saint Louis (2014-2017)

90 Credit hours towards Bachelor's of Elementary Education Degree

STATEMENT

I am a technical project manager adept in risk management, budgeting, and team collaboration. I have over 5 years of experience in education and retail, which has allowed me to develop my communication, management, and planning skills. I also have a strong interest in emerging technologies and graphic design.

EXPERIENCE

Assistant Director

First Academy | Maryland Heights, MO 08 / 2017 - 03/2020

- Upheld sound financial principles to keep programs operating within budget levels, maximizing resource utilization, while minimizing costs to reduce overall spending by 18% in 2019
- Collaborated on strategies to enhance student learning and behavior alongside parents and staff
- Established and optimized program schedules to cover planned needs while capitalizing on opportunities to improve student learning

Lead Teacher

Waverly Forest Academy | Saint Charles, MO 05 / 2016 - 08/2017

- Evaluated and revised lesson plans and course content to facilitate and moderate classroom
- Communicated with parents regularly to maintain student progress, schedule meetings, and increase student development
- Increased student academic performance by diversifying teaching techniques

Pet Care Assistant Manager

Petsmart | Chesterfield, MO 07/2014 - 05/2016

- Ensured that all animals were treated humanely and in accordance with local regulations and animal care guidelines
- Managed a filing system containing pet operations/care paperwork, sales records, and other vital information
- Assisted in the execution of all strategic merchandising initiatives to consistently drive sales